<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on Diomede T.</title><link>https://diomedet.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Diomede T.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 21:01:56 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://diomedet.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Note-taking is simple, right?!</title><link>https://diomedet.com/posts/note-takin-is-simple-right/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 21:01:56 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://diomedet.com/posts/note-takin-is-simple-right/</guid><description>TL;DR: Try Obsidian.md, is great!
In the past years, I found myself in need of some program that allows me to take notes just to remember things or to store some thoughts I have in that specific moment. When I was younger, I never minded too much where I wrote those notes. I thought that just the fact I wrote them would be enough to remember them, silly me&amp;hellip;
Since I realized that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t remember everything I wanted to, I&amp;rsquo;ve started searching for a tool that could help me, so my journey began.</description></item><item><title>Forecastle: my services Dashboard of choice</title><link>https://diomedet.com/posts/forecastle-my-services-dashboard-of-choice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 21:59:20 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://diomedet.com/posts/forecastle-my-services-dashboard-of-choice/</guid><description>Some weeks ago, I started the migration of my homelab from many docker-compose files to a more organized and reliable Kubernetes cluster.
In both these scenarios, I needed a way to collect all the links to the various services I have in one place. In the docker-compose implementation, I&amp;rsquo;ve used Heimdall, a great tool that gets the job done, but it requires some manual work. With the Kubernetes version of my homelab, I&amp;rsquo;m trying to automate as many tasks as possible.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes, external-dns, Pi-hole and a custom domain</title><link>https://diomedet.com/posts/kubernetes-external-dns-pihole-and-a-custom-domain/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 21:17:56 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://diomedet.com/posts/kubernetes-external-dns-pihole-and-a-custom-domain/</guid><description>During these days, I&amp;rsquo;m tidying up my homelab and found the necessity of having an internal domain to expose some apps inside my local network but not to the internet.
For example, I use Vault to store secrets, and I want an easy way to access the web-ui rather than using the IP address. The solution in Kubernetes is to create an Ingress; right now, I only have Ingresses with my main domain diomedet.</description></item><item><title>Expose an external resource with a Kubernetes Ingress</title><link>https://diomedet.com/posts/expose-an-external-resource-with-a-kubernetes-ingress/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 21:50:31 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://diomedet.com/posts/expose-an-external-resource-with-a-kubernetes-ingress/</guid><description>The other night I was wandering around my homelab and noticed that I didn&amp;rsquo;t correctly expose my new home assistant instance to the internet. Some months ago, home assistant (from now on HA) found its new permanent home, a Rasperry PI 4 4GB; since we&amp;rsquo;re in lockdown, I didn&amp;rsquo;t need to reach HA outside my local network.
I&amp;rsquo;m still working from home (and love it), but it&amp;rsquo;s time to fix this now.</description></item></channel></rss>